♪♪（太鼓）
Tailed Beast Counting Song!
All right, here we go!
（ナルト）『尾獣数え唄』
はじまり　はじまり！
One, "sleep is better than humans,"
says Shukaku.
♪♪「一つ　人より
居眠り守鶴」
Two, burning in fire, Matatabi.
♪♪「二つ　ファイヤー
燃えてる又旅」
Three, leave the water to Isobu.
♪♪「三つ　水なら
任せろ磯撫」
Four, hot as lava, Son Goku.
♪♪「四つ　溶岩
あついぜ孫悟空」
Five, always on the run, Kokuo.
♪♪「五つ　いつでも
駆け足　穆王」
Six, taking it easy and
not in a hurry, Saiken.
♪♪「六つ　無理せず」
♪♪「アワてず犀犬」
Seven, the flying leaf insect, Chomei.
♪♪「七つ　ナナフシ　空飛ぶ重明」
Eight, "Yeah!" is all it needs, Gyuki.
♪♪「八つ　やっぱり」
♪♪「ウィーだぜ　牛鬼」
Nine, "ko-kon" cries the mighty Kurama.
♪♪「九つ　ココンと
最強　九喇嘛」
All the Tailed Beasts have
finally come together.
♪♪「とうとうそろった　尾獣の仲間」
♪♪「ちょい　ムズだけどいい名前」
They're a little hard,
but they're nice names.
♪♪「みんな　立派な名前だね」
They're all splendid names.
♪♪「みんな　すてきな名前だね」
They're all wonderful names.
お次は　人柱力！
いくってばよ！
Next up, the Jinchuriki!
Here we go!
♪♪「一つ　ひどい
クマだよ我愛羅」
One, with terrible bags
under his eyes, Gaara.
♪♪「二つ　フニャ～ンと　猫なでユギト」
Two, with a silky voice like a cat, Yugito.
♪♪「三つ　水影
四代目のやぐら」
Three, the Fourth Mizukage, Yagura.
♪♪「四つ　４０年　四尾と老紫」
Four, together for forty years,
Four Tails and Roshi.
♪♪「五つ　いかついパワーのハン」
Five, tough and powerful, Han.
♪♪「六つ　無口な
着流しウタカタ」
Six, reserved and dressed
in a kimono, Utakata.
♪♪「七つ　なごむッス　くのいちフウ」
Seven, the heart-warming kunoichi, Fu.
♪♪「八つ　やばいよ
ラップのキラービー」
Eight, he's got crazy rap skills, Killer Bee.
♪♪「九つ　木ノ葉の
うずまきナルト」
Nine, the Leaf's Naruto Uzumaki.
♪♪「とっても強い　人柱力のみんな」
All the powerful Jinchuriki
have finally come together.
♪♪「尾獣と仲良くなれるかな？」
Can they become friends
with the Tailed Beasts?
♪♪「みんな　立派な忍だね」
They're all splendid shinobi.
♪♪「みんな　すてきな忍だね」
They're all wonderful shinobi.
softness can overcome hardness, but hardness can overcome softness
juuyokugou wo seishimashite gouyokujuu motatsu
if you're too focused on showing off, my alarm will go off
muchuu de kakkou tsukete mo hijou beru ga naru
walk fifty steps forward in a reckless style
gojuuppo ijou mo saki aruite chottotsumoushinna sutairu
you're moody and do as you please; no matter what I do, you ignore me
jiyuu de kibunya no kimi wa douyattatte mushi
there's a mystery that no one can solve, I shiver when the wind blows
darenimo tokenai nazo ga aru fukidashita kaze ni furueteru
I'll unravel this maze
kono meiro wo hodoite yaru
you laughed, will it rain tomorrow?
kimi ga waratta ashita wa ame kai
the wise light flickers
soumeina hikari ga chikachika hikaru
you've got to focus your eyes before the future changes
me wo korasanakucha mirai ga kawatte shimau mae ni
I'm sure, I'm sure this moment will be swept away
kitto kitto ima wo saratte iku
I have to be with you, otherwise the future might dry up
kimi to janakucha mirai wa kawaite shimau no kamo
hurry up, because I'm sure that we'll smile back on this moment
isoge kitto ima wo waratte iku
The Promise of Victory
– Heave... ho!
（２人）せ～の。
Hey, did you hear?
What?
Rumor is that Madara appeared
at the other battlefields.
Madara?
（シュン）おい　聞いたか？
（ナツ）何をだ？
We're at war with him,
so that's nothing unusual.
（シュン）他の戦場じゃあ
マダラが　現れたって話だぜ。
No! I'm not talking about that
shady-looking masked Madara.
（ナツ）マダラ？　そりゃ
そいつと戦争してんだから→
They're saying the real one appeared!
現れても
別に　おかしくはねえだろ。
What?!
（シュン）違えよ！　あのうさんくせえ
仮面のマダラじゃなくて→
What do you mean, "real one"?
本物が出たって話だよ！
Are you saying, that all this time,
he's been a fake?
（ナツ）あ？　おいおい。
No, what I mean is...
本物って　いったいなんだよ？
A super strong one,
just like the real Madara Uchiha
has appeared!
じゃあ　今までのは
偽物だったっていうのか？
（シュン）そうじゃなくて！
マジで→
And he's strong enough
to take on the Five Kage.
うちはマダラくらい
すげえ強えのが出たって話！
Take on the Five Kage?
Give me a break.
五影を相手に　互角以上だってよ。
It's true!
From what I heard,
五影が相手？　またまた～。
he hurled down meteorites
and created a jungle instantly.
ほんとだって！
俺の聞いた話じゃ
隕石を　ドッカンドッカン降らせたり→
Above all, he's a giant...
tens of meters tall.
一瞬で　ジャングルを作ったり→
A giant?!
何より　身の丈数十メートルの
巨人だって話だぞ。
巨人？
Well, they're just rumors...
Will you two cut it out?!
ハハハハ…。
Sure, the enemy's numbers
have dwindled.
だから　噂だって。
（ネジ）お前ら　いいかげんにしろ！
But we need to hunt down
the remaining enemy.
確かに　この戦場の敵は
残りわずか。
We're on a mission here.
しかし　その残党退治とはいえ
戦争中だ。
Get serious!
Focus on the enemy,
here and now!
少しは　緊張感を持て！
S-Sorry...
今は　目の前の敵に集中しろ！
You're right!
We weren't able to show
our stuff at this battle.
す　すみません。
そうっすね。
We'll show 'em on
the next battlefield!
この戦場じゃ　たいした手柄を
立てられなかったし…。
Okay.
次の戦場で暴れてやりますよ！
うむ…。
I'll pursue the enemy on the left!
You guys go to the right and
stop any remnants there!
（ネジ）俺は　左を追う！
Roger!
お前たちは　右のを仕留めてくれ！
（２人）はい！
– Let's go!
– Yeah!
いくぜ！
おうよ！
ぐわっ！
Another one bites the dust.
Hey! I'm the one that got him!
ヘヘ　一丁あがり。
おい　こいつをやったのは俺だろ。
What? Trying to take
all the credit?
（シュン）なんだよ
手柄を独り占めする気か？
Well, all you did was use
a little jutsu at the very end!
（ナツ）そっちこそ　最後にちょろっと
術　使っただけじゃねえか！
And that's what did him in!
Fine, I'll give you that...
（シュン）はあ？
それが　決め手だったよな！
（ナツ）百歩　譲って
そうだったとしてもだ！
But catching one weakling
is nothing to brag about.
って　ザコ１匹　競っても
しようがねえか。
だな。
Yeah...
ぐわっ！
Eight Trigrams: Air Palm!
（ネジ）八卦空掌！
Watch out, you two!
気をつけろ　２人とも！
Are you all right?!
大丈夫か？
た　助かりました。
You saved us...
The battle here finally ended.
やっと　この戦場での戦いも
終わるってのに→
If we were to get killed
when it was all over...
最後の最後に
やられたんじゃ…。
We were about to be humiliated...
シャレにならないとこでした…。
次の戦場は
いよいよ前線だからな。
The next battle is going
to be on the front lines.
SHINOBI
《シカク：うむ…　マダラは
五影が抑えていてくれる。
The Five Kage are
holding back Madara.
Sending Kakashi and Guy
out ahead
カカシとガイを先行させた策も
はまったようだ。
seems to have worked.
However, Naruto and the others
on the front line
それでも前線のナルトたちは
押され気味。
are under pressure.
Once the other battles wind down,
they'll rush to lend support.
だが　各戦場のケリがつきしだい
あいつらが駆けつける》
ん？　大丈夫か？
Are you all right?!
はい…　すみません。
Y-Yes... I'm sorry.
戦場で戦っている方々に
比べれば→
Compared to the others fighting
on the battlefield,
自分なんて　楽なほうなのに。
I have it easy, and yet...
いや…　ここには
ここにしかない緊張感もある。
No. We have our own kind of tension
that we have to contend with here.
気にすることはない。
Don't be so hard on yourself.
大事なときです。
This is a critical time for us.
大丈夫です！
I'm okay!
そうか…　すまないな。
All right. Thanks.
みんな　聞いてくれ！
Listen up, everyone!
戦争も最終局面へ
向かいつつある！
The war is entering its final stage!
すべての部隊の頭である
俺たちが　ミスをおかしては→
We are the central command center
for every company.
大事に至る！
無理をするなとは言えない。
We cannot afford to make
a single mistake!
I can't tell you not to overdo it.
だが　もう少しだ！
踏ん張ってほしい！
But hang in there a bit longer
and do your best!
頼む！
I'm counting on you!
（青）感知部隊には　この程度で
音を上げる者などいない。
There isn't a man
in the Sensory Unit
なあ　みんな！
who'd throw in the towel
with something like this!
（みんな）おう！
Right, guys?!
おっ…
俺たちだって　そうですよ！
– Right!
Neither would we!
ね？　いのいち隊長！
That goes for us too!
通信部隊は疲れ知らず。
Right, Captain Inoichi?!
それを見せてやりましょうよ！
Let's show 'em that
the Communications Unit is tireless!
（いのいち）うむ…　そうだな。
疲れたら　俺がフォローしてやるから
少しくらいなら休んでも…。
Hmm...
Right...
But if you get tired,
I'll take over...
だ～っ！　そこはビシッと→
俺についてこいで
いいじゃないっすか！
so it's okay to rest a bit.
Huh?! Don't take it easy on us!
空気読んでくださいよ！
Just tell us to follow you!
You have to learn to
go with the flow!
すまんな…。
そういうのは　苦手だ。
Sorry... I'm not good at
that kind of stuff.
《今ので　必要以上に
張り詰めていた緊張感がとれ→
That erased the pent-up anxiety
everyone was feeling...
and a sense of unity was born
at Headquarters.
本部に一体感が生まれた。
Headquarters, each battle company,
本部と各部隊
そして前線で戦うナルトたち。
and Naruto and the others fighting
on the front lines.
みんなの思いを
ひとつにできれば　この戦争…。
If we can stand united in purpose,
our foundation will be unshakeable
and we can overcome this war.
盤石の体制で
乗り切ることができる！》
ん？
こ　これは…。
どうした！？
Th-This is...?!
What happened?
（ナルト／九尾）尾獣玉！
– Tailed Beast Bomb!
いよいよ前線か…。
The front line at last...
待ってろよ　俺の手柄。
Just you wait!
I'll show you my stuff!
んっ　なんだ！？
（ナツ）な…　何が起きてるんだ？
Huh?! What is that?
What's happening?!
あれは前線のほうだな。
Isn't that in the direction
of the front line?
え？　あ　あそこに…。
これから行くのか。
Huh? L-Look over there.
（ネジ）うむ…　さっきのマダラの話→
Is that where we're going?
Yes...
噂話では
なかったのかもしれんな。
That talk earlier about Madara...
Maybe they weren't just rumors.
でかい手柄がありそうだぜ…。
That looks like...
（シュン）おお…　今度こそ手柄を。
something huge...
Yeah... Here's our chance
to show 'em.
Well done, Naruto!
I never thought you’d be able
to completely control Nine Tails.
（八尾）よくやったぞ　ナルト！
（マダラ）九尾まで
完全に　コントロール下に置くとはな。
However, it looks like you still can’t
maintain it for too long.
だが…
まだ　長続きはしないようだ。
So same old, same old.
それで　今までどおりだ。
It's not the same old, same old...
今までどおりじゃねえ…。
I just learned a whole bunch
of hard names all at once!
難しい名前　一度にたくさん
教えてもらったからよ！
Difficult names?
（マダラ）難しい名前だと？
What does that have to do
with anything?
それが　何だというのだ？
You don't know, do you?!
はぁ～ん…
お前は知らねえんだな！？
へっ！
べ～。　教えてやんねえよ！
I'm not gonna tell you!
Naruto gaining
such experience and strength
（ガイ）ナルトが　これほど成長したのを
目の当たりにすると…。
makes me feel old and feeble.
自分が　ずいぶんと
老いぼれに感じるな…。
What's the matter?
（カカシ）どうしたの？　いつもの
お前らしくないじゃない。
You're not being yourself!
It may sound funny
coming from me...
俺が言うのも　なんだけど…。
The springtime of our youth
is still far from over!
俺たちの青春も→
まだ　終わっちゃいないってことで
いかないか？
俺たちは　ここへ来て　まだ…。
We still have a lot of...
Quiet! Do you want to make me
feel even worse?
それ以上　言うな！
余計　むなしくなる。
それでこそ　ガイだ。
That's the Guy I know!
《あの顔…》
That expression...
《ん…　汗？》
Huh? Am I sweating?
《いや…　雨だ。
No, it's just rain.
俺が　あんなやつら相手に→
These fools could never
make me sweat.
汗を流すことなど
あるはずがない。
ナルトは　ただのサスケへの当て馬…。
Naruto was always
merely a pawn to test Sasuke.
俺にとっては
余興でしかないガキだったはず。
That brat's supposed to be
an amusement.
あいつの力は把握していた…。
I knew what his limits were.
この違和感は
力から　くるものではない…。
There's no way his power could be
pushing me this hard.
なら　何だというのだ！？
So what is it?!
いったい　何が…！？》
What's happened?
《いや…
そんなことは　どうでもいい。
It doesn't matter.
ナルトが何者かなんて
どうでもいいことだ…》
It doesn't matter who
or what Naruto is now...
この戦争より後
過去も未来もない…。
After this war is over,
存在すらも…
すべてが無意味になる。
there will be no past or future.
Nothing that exists now
will matter then!
A-Amazing...
（青）す…　すごいな…。
Did you guys feel that?
お前ら　今のを感じたか！？
I can't believe it.
There's no doubt.
That is the Nine Tails' power!
信じられませんよ…　間違いない。
あれが　九尾の力ですよ！
ああ…。
Yeah...
But I sense something...
slightly different.
《だが…　それとは少し違う
何かを感じる…》
What's the current situation?
その後の状況は？
Naruto Uzumaki is holding back
the Masked Madara
うずまきナルトが
とんでもない力で→
with an unbelievable amount
of power.
面のマダラを押さえてる…。
ありえないチャクラだ。
The chakra is unbelievable!
He's keeping him at bay.
いや…　むしろ　押してる。
It's just the four of them!
Naruto, Lord Bee, Kakashi and Guy!
ビー殿　カカシ殿　ガイ殿を含め
たった４人で…。
Inoichi!
いのいち！　ありったけの力で
このナルト側の状況を→
Relay Naruto's actions directly
into the minds
of the reinforcement troops
with everything you've got!
増援部隊全員の頭の中に
直接　語りかけてくれ！
Fifteen seconds is all we need!
１５秒でいい！
ここで　一気に士気を上げたい！
I want to boost everyone's morale
all at once!
あいつら４人が
全力で　ふんばってる。
Those four are giving it their all!
I want the rest of us here
to do everything we can too.
なら　ここは　ここでできることを
全力でするぞ！
Convey their resolve to everyone!
あいつらの思いを伝えるんだ！
To everyone?!
全員って…　そんなことをしたら→
It will overload the Chakra Network.
チャクラの経絡系に
負担がかかりすぎて…。
下手すると…。
Make one mistake and...
フッ　ムチャを言う…。
You ask for the extreme.
１０秒だ！
いのいちさん！
Make it ten seconds!
Master Inoichi!
すまない…
だが　今　大切なことだ！
Sorry, but this is critical!
短い分　上手くまとめてくれよ。
Make it short,
but make it count!
口は上手いほうじゃないが
任せとけ！
I'm not good with words,
but you can count on me!
《本部より伝達！
Message from HQ!
増援ポイントにて　状況優勢！
We have the upper hand at
the battle reinforcement point!
つまり　うずまきナルトが
ふんばってくれてる！
Naruto Uzumaki is standing firm!
俺たち　連合が守るべき
ナルトが　ビー殿が！
The ones we must protect at all costs,
Naruto and Lord Bee...
前線で　強い思いを持って
戦ってくれてる！
are fighting with everything
they've got on the front line!
ガイも　カカシも同じくだ！
Guy and Kakashi are there too!
そして　連合のみんなも
その強い思いに加わってくれ。
To everyone in the Allied Force...
I need all of you to add to
their mighty hearts!
その　みんなの強い思いが…》
Amplify it with your mighty hearts!
《この戦争の　勝利への予言だ！》
I promise you, victory is now!
ガハッ…　ハァ　ハァ…。
やっぱ…　口下手だな　俺は。
I'm bad with words, after all.
結局２０秒も…　かかっちまった…。
It took me 20 seconds.
ハァ　ハァ…。
隊長…。
《ああ…。
Captain...
それが　お前の思いの強さだ》
Yeah...
That just shows how mighty
your heart is...
ハァ　ハァ…　すまねぇ…。
ハァ　ハァ…。
Sorry...
《ヒナタ：ナルト君…
私は　あなたをずっと…。
ずっと…　ずっと追いかけてきた。
Naruto...
I've run, and run after you
my whole life.
そして　今も追いかけてる》
And I'm still running after you.
《でも　この戦争が終わったら→
もう　あなたを
追いかけるのはやめにします。
But when this war is over.
次は　ナルト君の横にいて→
I'm going to stop running.
しっかり
あなたの手を握ったまま→
同じ歩幅で歩きたいんです。
I'll stand with you.
I'll hold your hand.
待っていてください》
And I'll walk with you by your side.
《キバ：ナルト　お前にゃ　昔から
しっかり　マーキングしといたんだ。
So please wait for me!
俺のライバルとしてよ。
Naruto...
I marked you as
my rival ages ago.
俺が駆けつけるまで
マダラの相手は頼んだぜ！》
《シノ：俺の忍術で
ナルトを完璧にサポートする。
Hang tight against Madara,
until I get there!
なぜなら　…は必要ない！》
I'll support you completely
with my ninjutsu, Naruto.
（シカマル）うまくやってるようだな
ナルトのやつ。
And a reason...
is not necessary!
あいつのことだ…
ムチャやってる以外→
想像つかねえが　ああ見えて
実は　頭がキレるほうだからな。
Naruto is doing a good job.
I can't see him being
anything other than reckless.
（チョウジ）ナルトは　バカで　僕は　デブ
ってのがお決まりだったけど→
But despite his looks,
he's a pretty sharp guy.
意外と　そうじゃなかったり
するんだよね。
People thought Naruto was dumb
and I was fat.
《待っててね　ちょいバカナルト。
すらっとチョウジが今行くよ！》
But that really wasn't the case!
冷静に
策を練るタイプじゃないけどな。
Wait for me, smart Naruto!
《だからこそ　俺がいる。
Skinny Choji is coming to help you!
待ってろ　ナルト　もうすぐ行く！》
He's not the type to strategize calmly.
That's what I'm here for.
《いの：父さん　ありがとう。
So you just wait, Naruto.
I'll be right there!
ナルトの強い思いってのを
父さんがみんなに伝えてくれた。
その予言　必ず実現させなきゃ！》
Thank you, Dad!
You transmitted Naruto's mighty heart
to everyone.
《テンテン：ガイ先生　大丈夫かな？
ちゃんと　ナルトを
守ってあげてるかな？
That promise must be fulfilled!
カカシ先生もいることだし
大丈夫だと思うけど》
I wonder if Guy Sensei is all right?!
I hope he's protecting Naruto!
（サイ）雨が降っていなければ
超獣偽画で飛んでいけたのに！
Kakashi Sensei is there too.
（リー）文句より
スピードアップですよ　サイさん！
I think they'll manage, but...
ガイ先生の勇姿
ナルト君の勇姿に応え→
If it wasn't raining,
己を貫き通すときです！
we could have flown on
my Super Beast Scrolls.
うん。
Stop complaining, Sai.
Pick up your speed!
《これが仲間っていう感覚。
We must follow Guy Sensei
and Naruto's examples.
今の僕には
もう　はっきりとわかるよ。　ナルト》
This is the time for us
to exceed ourselves!
Uh-huh...
This is camaraderie...
《サクラ：ナルト
あんたは　木ノ葉を救った。
I have a really good grasp
of it now, Naruto.
そして　今度は
忍の世界を救おうとしている。
いつもいつも
こんな大変なことばっかり→
Naruto...
You saved the Hidden Leaf.
任されることになっちゃってる。
でも　今度は　あんたが
何を言おうが一緒に…。
And now, you are trying to
save the shinobi world.
私だけじゃない。
And we've always, always put
the burden on your shoulders.
今度こそ
みんなで一緒に戦おう！》
But this time,
no matter what you say...
you'll have help.
Not just me.
This time,
we'll all fight together!
let's keep walking
itsuka kitto kitto tadori tsuku tame ni
so we'll be sure to get there someday
ima wa madamada arukou
when I was young, I had a guitar as a toy
osanai koro te ni shita omocha kawaridatta gitaa
we just made noises, but that was enough to keep me engrossed
tada otowodasu hontou soredakeni muchu ni natte ita
giving up seems simple, but it's incredibly difficult
akirameru no wa kantan na youde ichiban muzukashii
I'll start singing today too
sousa boku wa kyou mo utau yo
I believe that my dream will come true I want to believe
dakara sou yume wa kanau shinjitai shinjitai
if I reach even one person
tatta hitori demo todoite kuretara
until I lose my voice
kono koe kareru made
I believe that everyone's dream can come true, I want to believe
dare demo yume wa kanau shinjiteru shinjiteru
the future is sure to change to a color you like better
dakara motto motto mirai wa korekara sukinairo ni kawaru yo
let's hold on to our dreams
yume wo daite arukou
We should find Sasuke before
we get mixed up in this war!
＜旬の魚が大好きな豆助＞
Suigetsu, why are you here?
Are you in Team Hawk just to cause trouble
with Sasuke and Karin.
I would love to break
those two losers up for good!
豆助　きょうのお魚は
今が旬のあれよ
I can't help it!
You're reprehensible,
you know that?
＜　その魚とは…＞
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Eyes That See in the Dark"
I hate you all.
＜　それは身が厚い皮で
覆われていることから→